Alan Quintero

Computer Systems Engineer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: alan_q_b@hotmail.com

US cell phone number: (+1)-805-625-1660

Skype: alan.quintero3

LinkedIn: https://mx.linkedin.com/in/alan-quintero-a7770a87

Website: http://alanquintero.com.mx/

Citizenship: US citizen.

SUMMARY

I am an experienced Software Engineer with a proven career track of 4 years as a Java developer, specialized on Java SE and Java EE. I have worked in some sectors, creating new solutions, and providing enhancements for existing Web Applications based on Java technologies. I have also developed web solutions through open-source Front-end and Back-end technologies. I am familiarized with a 100% Agile environment. Eager to learn modern technologies. Training to improve my technical skills.

EXPERIENCE

Technology Analyst.

June 2017 to Present

Infosys - Sunnyvale, California USA

- Internal Web Application: Develop backend to create and improve an existent Web Application.
- Analyze requirements to develop new code and modify existing code using best practices of programming. Create unit and integration tests.
- Client: Apple

<u>Technologies involved:</u> Java 8, J2EE, Spring Boot, Spring Security, RESTful, JSON, JDBC, Hibernate, JUnit 4, Git, Oracle SQL, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse

Software Engineering Sr. Analyst.

August 2016 to June 2017

Accenture - Monterrey, Mexico

- Mass Media Services: Develop back-end and front-end to implement a Web Application based on an
 existent one.
- Analyze and implemented code, create unit test and reviewed code from other team members.
- Took the initiative to create reference and technical documentation useful for new joiners.
- Modify existent code using best practices of programming.
- Client: Charter

<u>Technologies involved:</u> Java 8, J2EE, Spring Boot, Spring Security, RESTful, Microservices, JDBC, Hibernate, JUnit 4, Mockito, Selenium 2, Git, MySQL, Teradata, Sonar, Apache Tomcat, Jenkins, JSON, XML, Swagger, Google Checkstyle, Eclipse, Atlassian Suite, and Agile Methodology

Java Developer

April 2015 to August 2016

Tata Consultancy Services - Guadalajara, Mexico

- Health and Insurance Services: Develop back-end and front-end to implement a new line of business for a Web Application.
- Analyze and implement solutions on the back-end and sometimes on the front-end, test the code and create technical documentation.
- Point of contact of Mexico team. Analyze and estimate tasks for the team, conduct technical trainings.
 In charge of a team of three people.
- Conduct Java training to beginner programmers with the goal of estimate and create a Java Desktop Application to reserve conference rooms.
- Client: USAA

<u>Technologies involved:</u> Java 6, J2EE, JUnit 4, JavaScript, JSP, HTML5, MySQL, Eclipse, IBM Rational Team Concert (RTC), and Scrum

Java Developer

July 2013 to March 2015

Softtek - Aguascalientes, Mexico

- Financial Services: Develop back-end to migrate a Desktop Application to a Web Application.
- Analyze, identify and estimate the requirements.
- Designed a JSON response, analyze, and implement code, create queries to retrieve Database information, create unit test and test using manual testing on web pages.
- Analyze and create a diagram proposal for some tables of the Data Base.
- Modify code using best practices of programming.
- Client: General Electric

<u>Technologies involved:</u> Java 6, J2EE, Spring MVC 3, Maven 3, RESTful, JUnit 4, JSON, iBatis, JDBC, TortoiseGit, Jetty, Sonar, Oracle PL/SQL, Eclipse, and Agile Methodology

PERSONAL EXPERIENCE

Website: http://alanquintero.com.mx/
Github: https://github.com/alan0092

<u>Technologies involved:</u> Java 8, J2EE, Spring Boot, Spring MVC 4, Spring Security, Spring JPA, JDBC, Maven 3, RESTful, JUnit 4, Mockito, PowerMock, JSON, Hibernate, MySQL, HyperSQL, PostgreSQL, Jetty, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Heroku, Git, AngularJS, Node.js, AWS

EDUCATION

August 2010 to December 2014

Universidad Autonoma de Aguascalientes

Aguascalientes, Mexico

Bachelor's Degree: Computer Systems Engineering

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

Android Certified Professional – June 03, 2016 Java SE 6 Programmer – June 04, 2015

SKILLS HIGHLIGHTS

- Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring JPA, RESTful, Microservices, Maven, JUnit, Mockito, PowerMock, Selenium, Hibernate, iBatis, JDBC, Selenium
- JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5, JSP, JSON, XML, AJAX, AngularJS (basics), Node.js (basics)
- MySQL, Oracle PL/SQL, PostgreSQL, HyperSQL
- Git
- Jenkins, Sonar, Swagger, Google Checkstyle, Heroku, AWS (basics)
- Apache Tomcat, Jetty
- · Windows, Android, Linux

LANGUAGES

English – Business Level Spanish – Native